<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Beep Boop Bop]]></title>
  <link href="http://sammarcus.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sammarcus.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-09T09:46:35-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sammarcus.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sam Marcus]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello? Cómo Estás!]]></title>
    <link href="http://sammarcus.github.io/blog/2014/10/09/hello-como-estas/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-09T09:17:46-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sammarcus.github.io/blog/2014/10/09/hello-como-estas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>APIs, or Application programming interfaces, are an incredibly useful component in software development that allow developers to build things that speak to other programs. The first time I was introduced to APIs was when Steve Jobs announced the addition of apps to the iOS ecosystem. At the time, believe it or not, iPhones did not have an App Store and developers were eager to build but unable to ship. in iOS 2 Apple permitted access to an extremely limited set of capabilities and were very strict in App review and approval, as the first apps often tried to utilize private APIs.</p>

<p><img src="http://gdeluxe.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/IOS-HISTORY.jpg" alt="iOS API" /></p>


<p>In Ruby, the implications are equally empowering. Users often have the expectation that things &ldquo;just work” with each other, and APIs allow developers to make that happen. From a developer’s point of view, offering an API that is both clearly documented and easy to implement will encourage other developers to “speak” to your program and leverage core functionalities. APIs are absolutely essential and it wouldn’t be unreasonable to consider them the very backbone of the &lsquo;Internet of Things’. From music services to fitness devices to social networkings sites, APIs power the internet and fulfill the never ending expectation of high performing tools. When developers choose not to create these pathways for communication with their tools, they are called undocumented or private APIs. Although they may work on a temporary basis, because these use things that may be phased out in the future they are vulnerable to break at any point in time.</p>

<p>No matter the language or platform, APIs will continue to propel the internet we use today to new heights and functionality!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Post on Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://sammarcus.github.io/blog/2014/10/08/my-first-post-on-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-08T18:52:07-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://sammarcus.github.io/blog/2014/10/08/my-first-post-on-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello, world!!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
